now let's look at the shared memory
version of the same program we still
have the same size of the overall array
and the same number of processor cores
but this time they can all access the
same memory so we can just put the whole
array in memory we will have the total
sum and each of them will be computing
its own sum so because this arrays in
the shared memory each processor will
sum up its own part of the array
the big difference occurs not only here
where we are actually able to just
access the part of the array we want
but also in how we can compute the sum
instead of having to explicitly send
the elements of the array to one of the
cores here each core can access the all
sum variable to compute the final sum
so what they do is they synchronize so
they have a critical section around this
and then each course simply takes the
overall sum and adds its own sum into it
and then freeze the log so that the next
core can do it so the course can do this
in any order they want we don't have to
control that order or anything all that
needs to happen is that all of them have
added the sum together and now
we still have to make sure that one of
the cores prints out the sum but because
this can be done in any order core 0
could be the one
that does this first and then prints out
only its part of the sum because the
others have not updated this yet so we
need to add code here to have what's
called a barrier where basically we put
a synchronization here that makes all of
the cores wait for everybody to arrive
before they proceed to ensure that core
zero when it does this does it only when
everybody else has arrived to this point
and has incremented the sum already
one of the nice properties of this is
not only that it makes it more explicit
who does what so that we don't have to
think about this as being basically four
different versions of code
there is no need to distribute the array
the whole array is all the time in the
shared memory we just choose who's going
to access what